Kamal Youssef

₹ 732-910-3993 ★ Kamal.Youssef60@gmail.com in Linkedin.com/in/kamal-youssef-925487121

SUMMARY

Software Developer with five years of experience in programming, testing, and establishing system improvements. Currently working as a Solutions Architect and Developer in the automation workspace. Equally proficient with front end software development, machine learning methods, and automation scripting.

EDUCATION

New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT)

B.S. Information Technology (Network & Information Security / Web Application Development)

Graduated: May 2021

Major GPA: 3.75

Relevant Coursework: System Administration (Linux), Web Applications Development, Ethical Hacking for SysAdmins, Computer System and Networks, Advanced Programing (Java)

Technical Skills: UiPath(<1yr), AWS (<1yr), Python (4yrs), HTML/CSS (4yrs), SQL (3yrs), JavaScript (3yr), WordPress (2yr), Visual Studio/ASP.NET(1yr), ReactJS(1yr), Machine Learning(1yr), Git, Jira, Databricks

WORK EXPERIENCE

Merck (CTO - Foundational Automation) Kenilworth, NJ (ETR) Solutions Architect & Developer

July 2021 - Present

- Implemented a new CI/CD Platform for RPA OCR automation solutions utilizing **Azure** and cloud services leading the team toward proper Agile practices and infrastructure automation.
- Designed a more reliable, secure, and controlled workflow for managing all future OCR/Lambda projects for a team of 5 developers and DevOps platforms engineers.
- Co-developer on one-time HH automation that assists in matching discounted returns with HERSA customers Designed project architecture integrating UiPath & AWS, projected to save business ~ 1440 (.75 FTE) hours of manual work per year

Merck Research Labs IT Intern Rahway, NJ

June 2020 - August 2020

- Used Databricks to train and improve deep learning models to predict properties of potential molecules in Drug Discovery and Early Development
- Worked closely with the HPC (High Performance Computing) DevOps team to design a series of Deep Learning models using TensorFlow in **Python** to improve the efficiency of HPC scheduling

Johnson & Johnson Raritan, NJ Technology Co-op **January 2019 – August 2019**

- Coordination of Technology Lifecycle Management Activities ensured support of legacy operating systems by coordinating OS upgrades
- Used **ASP.NET** framework, HTML/CSS, **JavaScript**, and **C#** to develop a dashboard showing workload automation job configuration details for the internal team, as well as end-users

ACTIVITIES / LEADERSHIP

St. Mark's Church Jersey City, NJ Youth Leader July 2015 - Present

- Organize Sunday curriculum for each subject throughout the year
- Create weekly lesson plans and educate children in weekly religious lessons every Saturday and Sunday
- Schedule and organize field trips monthly

Coptic Society NJIT Newark, NJ Vice President and IT Coordinator

March 2018 - May 2021

- Pilot board meetings, set semester goals, disseminate action items and follow up on task completion
- Coordinate Club events such as Habitat for Humanity, visiting hospitals, and various on and off-campus events
- Increased club awareness and participation by 40 percent with the implementation of the new website

HONORS/AWARDS/CERTIFICATES

AWS Associate Solutions Architect (Certificate)

Oct. 17, 2021 - Present

To contribute to major platform architecture decisions and changes

Merck Silver Cyber Security Champion (Certificate)

September 2021 - Present

• Completed bronze and silver cyber security courses provided by Merck

September 2017 – July 2021

NJIT Faculty Scholarship

• Selected among 1000K+ applicants for 4-year academic achievement scholarship

Kamal Youssef

₹ 732-910-3993 ★ Kamal.Youssef60@gmail.com in Linkedin.com/in/kamal-youssef-925487121

PROJECTS

Constellar, Merck Project

November 2019 - Present

• Lead DevOps on Constellar platform development that connects experts within the company based on advanced Al/NLP techniques – guiding the transition to a scalable multi-tenant deployment in the AWS Cloud